Whoever wins...we lose.
AVP: Alien vs. Predator is a adventure, science fiction,
action film directed by Paul W. S. Anderson.
When scientists discover something near Antarctica that appears to be a
buried Pyramid, they send a research team out to investigate.
Little do they know that they are about to step into a hunting ground
where Aliens are grown as sport for the Predator race.
Alexa Woods, played by Sanaa Lathan.
Charles Bishop Weyland, played by Lance Henriksen.
Scar, played by Ian Whyte.
Sebastian de Rosa, played by Raoul Bova.
Graeme Miller, played by Ewen Bremner.
Maxwell Stafford, played by Colin Salmon.
Predator (stylized on-screen as AVP: Alien vs.
Predator) is a 2004 American science fiction action
horror film and the first in the Alien vs.
Predator franchise.
It is written and directed by Paul W.
Anderson, and stars Sanaa Lathan, Raoul Bova, Lance Henriksen,
Ewen Bremner, Colin Salmon, and Tommy Flanagan.
In the film, scientists are caught in the crossfire of an ancient battle between
Aliens and Predators as they attempt to escape a bygone Antarctic pyramid.
It adapts a crossover bringing together the creatures of the Alien and Predator series, a concept
which originated in a 1989 comic book written by Randy Stradley and Chris Warner.
Anderson wrote the story, with the creators of the Alien franchise, Dan O'Bannon and Ronald Shusett receiving additional story credit due
to the incorporation of elements from the Alien series, and Anderson and Shane Salerno adapted the story into a screenplay.
Their writing was influenced by Aztec mythology, the comic book
series, and the writings of Erich von Däniken.
Predator was theatrically released on 13 August 2004.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics and grossed $177.4
million worldwide against a production budget of $60–70 million.
A sequel, Aliens vs.
Predator: Requiem, was released in 2007.
The film explores themes of space marine, saving the
world, predator, praise, pyramid.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.